Dorothy Liebes
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Writings, 1920-1969, Series 4:; (Boxes 10-11; 1.25 linear ft.)
  - Writings by Other Authors, 1944-1969, 4.2:
    - Script, about Liebes Exhibition at City Art Museum, St. Louis, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Speeches, 1947-1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Artwork, 1938-1963, Series 5:; (Boxes 11, 19, OV 22; 0.35 linear ft.)
  5.1: Artwork by Dorothy Liebes, circa 1930s-circa 1960s
  5.2: Artwork by Other Artists, 1938-1963
  - Artwork by Dorothy Liebes, circa 1930s-circa 1960s, 5.1:
    Artwork by Liebes consists of designs, feather weavings, a small hooked composition, a tapestry sample and textiles. Textile samples produced by the Dorothy Liebes Studio, as well as some that may have been mass produced based on designs by Liebes, can be found in Series 8: Samples.
    - Designs, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Feather Weavings, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Hooked Composition, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Tapestry Sampler, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Artwork by Other Artists, 1938-1963, 5.2:
    This subseries includes designs by Lawrence Colwell for interiors, furniture, and product packaging. Researchers should note that additional material concerning Colwell can be found in Series 7: Scrapbooks. Other items of note are caricatures of Liebes and a Kokemono screen.
    - Architectural Drawings, Floor Plans, 1963, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Caricatures of Dorothy Liebes, undated, (see also: OV 22) (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Designs, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Designs by Lawrence J. Colwell, undated, (see also: Box 19) (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Drawings, 1938, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Kokemono Screen, undated, (see: RD 58) (Box 11)
    - Monogram designed for Dorothy Wright Liebes (print), undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Paintings, undated, (see also: OV 22) (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Posters, undated, (original prints; see: OV 22) (Box 11)
    - Prints, undated, (see also: Box 19 and OV 22) (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Designs by Lawrence J. Colwell, undated, (3 folders; see also: Box 11) (Box 19 (sol))
    - Paintings, undated, (see also: Box 11 and OV 22) (Box 19 (sol))
    - Prints, undated, (see also: Box 11 and OV 22) (Box 19 (sol))
    - Caricature of Dorothy Liebes; Painting; Prints (including posters with original artwork), 1947-1959, undated (Box OV 22)
    - Painting, 1947, (see also Boxes 11, 19) (Box OV 22)
    - Posters, undated, (original prints) (Box OV 22)
    - Print, 1959, (see also Boxes 11, 19) (Box OV 22)
- Financial Records, 1947-1968, Series 6:; (Box 12; 0.25 linear ft.)
  - Financial Summaries, 1947-1957, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Investments (summary statements), 1957-1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Taxes (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Federal, 1951-1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - New York City, 1948-1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - New York State, 1957-1966 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Scrapbooks, 1933-1970, Series 7:; (Box 20, BV 24-56; 3.7 linear ft.)
  This series contains 33 bound scrapbook volumes of printed matter and publicity material, photographs, and a small number of documents relating to Liebes' professional achievements, commissions, and studio. There are also loose pages from a volume featuring the work of designer Lawrence Colwell.
  - Loose Pages (from Scrapbook about Lawrence Colwell), undated (Box 20 (sol))
  - Loose Pages (from unidentified Scrapbook), undated (Box 20 (sol))
  - Scrapbook, 1933-1938 (Box BV 24)
  - Scrapbook, 1934-1944 (Box BV 25)
  - Scrapbook, 1939 (Box BV 26)
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1940 (Box BV 27)
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1940 (Box BV 28)
  - Scrapbook, 1942-1943 (Box BV 29)
  - Scrapbook, 1940 (Box BV 30)
  - Scrapbook, 1943-1945 (Box BV 31)
  - Scrapbook, 1944-1945 (Box BV 32)
  - Scrapbook, 1945-1946 (Box BV 33)
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1947 (Box BV 34)
  - Scrapbook, 1947, (1 of 2) (Box BV 35)
  - Scrapbook, 1947, (2 of 2) (Box BV 36)
  - Scrapbook, 1948 (Box BV 37)
  - Scrapbook, 1949 (Box BV 38)
  - Scrapbook, 1950 (Box BV 39)
  - Scrapbook, 1951 (Box BV 40)
  - Scrapbook, 1952 (Box BV 41)
  - Scrapbook, 1953 (Box BV 42)
  - Scrapbook, 1954 (Box BV 43)
  - Scrapbook, 1955 (Box BV 44)
  - Scrapbook, 1956 (Box BV 45)
  - Scrapbook, 1957 (Box BV 46)
  - Scrapbook, 1959 (Box BV 47)
  - Scrapbook, 1960 (Box BV 48)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1962 (Box BV 49)
  - Scrapbook, 1963 (Box BV 50)
  - Scrapbook, 1964 (Box BV 51)
  - Scrapbook, 1965 (Box BV 52)
  - Scrapbook, 1966 (Box BV 53)
  - Scrapbook, 1967-1968 (Box BV 54)
  - Scrapbook, 1968-1969 (Box BV 55)
  - Scrapbook, 1970 (Box BV 56)
- Samples, circa 1850-1855, circa 1930-circa 1970, Series 8:; (Boxes 12-14, 20; 2.11 linear ft.)
  This series consists primarily of textile swatches designed by Liebes. The samples may have been woven by Liebes, by weavers in her studio, or been mass produced elsewhere. There are also samples of textiles from other sources, a collection of historical samples of 19th century English, French, and Viennese printed cottons mounted on sheets, and a small number of fiber and leather samples.
  - Fiber Samples, circa 1930-circa 1970, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 8-10)
  - Leather Samples, circa 1930-circa 1970 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Textile Samples, Studio, 1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 12-13)
  - Textile Samples, Liebes' Studio, circa 1930-circa 1970, (13 folders) (Box 13, Folder 14-26)
  - Textile Samples, Liebes' Studio, circa 1930-circa 1970, (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - Textile Samples, Miscellaneous Sources, circa 1930-circa 1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Historical Samples, circa 1850-1855, (2 folders) (Box 20 (sol))
- Calendars and Interviews, 1945-1971, Series 9:; (Boxes 14-15; 1.45 linear ft.)
  In addition to calendars, this series contains a sound recording on 5" magnetic tape from the Milwaukee Journal Radio Station and a transcript of an interview with Liebes on Nancy Craig's radio show, "Woman of Tomorrow."
  - Calendars, Desk Diaries, 1948-1971, (9 folders; 23 volumes) (Box 14, Folder 5-13)
  - Calendars, Monthly, 1949-1969, (7 folders; 28 calendars) (Box 15, Folder 1-7)
  - Sound Recording, circa 1956 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Transcript of Interview with Dorothy Liebes (Nancy Craig's radio show, "Woman of Tomorrow"), 1945 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Printed Material, 1897-1970, Series 10:; (Boxes 15-16, 20-21, OV 23; 1.05 linear ft.)
  Printed material consists of articles, exhibition catalogs, press releases, reproductions, and miscellaneous items about or mentioning Dorothy Liebes and her work, and topics of interest to her, such as weavers and weaving, the textile industry, art and design.
  Additional printed material can be found in Series 3: Subject Files and Series 7: Scrapbooks.
  - Advertisements Featuring/Mentioning Dorothy Liebes Textiles, 1949-1959, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Articles, About/Mentioning Liebes, 1918, 1930s-1970s, undated, (6 folders; see also: box 20) (Box 15, Folder 11-16)
  - Articles, Art and Design, 1941-1965, undated (see also: box 20) (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Articles, By Liebes, 1943-1965 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Articles, Family, 1897-1951, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Articles, Miscellaneous Topics, 1946-1962, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Articles, Textile Industry, 1946-1955, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Awards (Dorothy Liebes on Jury), 1953-1964 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Business Cards and Flyers about the Dorothy Liebes Studio, 1949-1953, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Liebes Exhibitions, 1949-1970, undated, (see also: Box 20) (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Other Weavers and Designers, 1926-1963, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, 1940-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Exhibition Prospectuses, 1956-1960 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lectures and Classes, Announcements and Programs, Liebes, 1946-1962, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Items Mentioning Dorothy Liebes, 1947-1952, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Publications (art related), 1938-1969, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases About/Mentioning Dorothy Liebes, 1948, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, undated, (see also: Box 20, OV 23) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Articles, About/Mentioning Liebes, undated, (see also Box 15) (Box 20 (sol))
  - Articles, Art and Design ("Old Art Treasures from Japan's Needles and Looms"), 1949, (see also Box 15) (Box 20 (sol))
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Liebes Exhibitions, undated, (see also Box 15) (Box 20 (sol))
  - Reproductions, Artwork, undated, (see also Boxes 16, 21, OV 23) (Box 20 (sol))
  - Reproductions, Les Batiks de Java (plates in portfolio), undated (Box 20 (sol))
  - Reproductions, Broideries Hindoues (plates in portfolio), undated (Box 20 (sol))
  - Reproductions, Les Petits Alphabets du Brodeur (loose plates), undated (Box 21 (sol))
  - Reproductions, 80 Toiles Imprimées et Indiennes de Traite (plates in portfolio), undated (Box 21 (sol))
  - Reproductions, Tapis Modernes (plates in portfolio), undated (Box 21 (sol))
  - Reproductions, Surasundari: Photographs by Raymond Burnier (plates in portfolio), undated (Box OV 23)
- Photographs, 1897-1970, Series 11:; (Boxes 16-18, 21, BV 57; 1.5 linear ft.)
  This series contains photographs of artwork (not by Liebes); people including Liebes, Relman "Pat" Morin, Frank Lloyd Wright, and many unidentified individuals and groups; places such as travel destinations; textiles and miscellaneous subjects. Color slides, transparencies, and negatives can also be found here.
  Additional photographs can be found in many of the files in Series 3: Subject Files, and some of the volumes in Series 7: Scrapbooks.
  This series is arranged as 6 subseries:
  11.1: Artwork, circa 1930s-circa 1970s
  11.2: People, 1897-1970
  11.3: Places, 1937-1941
  11.4: Textiles, 1936-1967
  11.5: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1940s
  11.6: Color Slides, Color Transparencies, and Negatives, 1939-1947
  - Artwork, undated, 11.1:
    Found here are prints of photos of artwork by Leger, Murany, Picasso, Cunliffe, Gabo, Guino and unidentified artists.
    - Paintings, circa 1930s-circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Sculpture, circa 1930s-circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Tapestries, circa 1930s-circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - People, 1897-1970, 11.2:
    - Liebes, Dorothy, 1930s-1960s, undated, (2 folders; see also: Box 21) (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
    - Liebes, Dorothy, in Studio/at Loom, 1930s-1940s, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Liebes, Dorothy, with Others, 1940s-1960s, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Liebes, Dorothy, with Weavers, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Liebes, Dorothy, with Relman "Pat" Morin, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Liebes, Dorothy, with Relman "Pat" Morin, Frank Lloyd Wright, and Others at Taliesen West, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Morin, Relman "Pat", 1944, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Morin, Relman "Pat", with Others, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1947, (see: Box 21) (Box 16)
    - Children (unidentified), 1937-1969, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Family ?, 1897-1915, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Groups,1938-1970, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Men, 1923-1953, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 24-25)
    - Weavers, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Women, 1930s-1957, undated, (see also: Box 21) (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Liebes, Dorothy, circa 1940-circa 1943, (see also: Box 16) (Box 21 (sol))
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1947, (see also Box 16) (Box 21 (sol))
    - Women (unidentified), undated, (see also Box 16) (Box 21 (sol))
  - Places, 1937-1941, 11.3:
    - France, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Hawaii, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - New York, undated, (see Box 21) (Box 16)
    - Unidentified, 1937-1941, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - New York City, undated (Box 21 (sol))
  - Textiles, 1936-1967, 11.4:
    This subseries contains photographs of Liebes exhibition installations at various venues, garments made from Liebes fabric and interiors and window displays featuring textiles by Liebes. There is also an album of interiors featuring Liebes textiles.
    - Exhibition Installations, 1942-circa 1948, undated (Box 16)
    - Garments, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Interiors, 1936-1962, undated, (2 folders; see also: Box 21, BV 57) (Box 16, Folder 32-33)
    - Textiles by Liebes, 1967, undated (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Textiles by Other Weavers, undated (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Window Displays, undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Photograph Album, undated, (see also: Boxes 16 and 21) (Box BV 57)
    - Interiors, undated, (see also: Box 16, BV 57) (Box 21 (sol))
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1940s, 11.5:
    - "Arts and Skills" (American Red Cross program), 1940s (Box 17 (pam), Folder 1)
    - Dogs, 1948 (Box 17 (pam), Folder 2)
    - Looms, undated (Box 17 (pam), Folder 3)
    - Plants, undated (Box 17 (pam), Folder 4)
  - Color Slides, Color Transparencies, and Negatives, 1939-1947, 11.6:
    - Color Slides, Textiles by Dorothy Liebes, undated, (35-mm) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Color Transparencies (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Interiors, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - People, Liebes and Liebes with Others, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - People, Groups, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Places, Unidentified, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Textiles by Liebes, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Negatives (Box 18 (hol), Folder 1)
      - Artwork (not by Liebes), undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects, undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 3)
      - People (Box 18 (hol), Folder 4)
        - "Allan and Bogie, Palmer and Harry, Los Angeles," 1941 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 5)
        - "Berkeley weekend, Peter and Billy," 1942 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 6)
        - "Bill's Ranch," 1944 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 7)
        - Dorothy Liebes; Dorothy Liebes with Others, undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 8)
        - "Dorothy and Cynthia at Barbara Burke's," 1942 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 9)
        - "Family," 1939 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 10)
        - "Family in Berkeley," 1940, 1942, (2 folders) (Box 18 (hol), Folder 11-12)
        - Family – "Louise at Mother's," undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 13)
        - "Greer and Lucy," 1940 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 14)
        - "Helen and Fij Ross," 1939 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 15)
        - "Jane, Dorothy, and Cynthia at Monterey," undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 16)
        - "New York," 1944 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 17)
        - "Peter and Dorothy," 1942 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 18)
        - "Peter and Dorothy at Yosemite," 1942 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 19)
        - "Peter Grimm," 1941 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 20)
        - "Spring, 1942," 1942 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 21)
        - "Spring Trip East," 1942 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 22)
        - "Studio," undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 23)
        - "Summer, 1940," 1940 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 24)
        - "Summer, 1941 – Hornbrook," 1941 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 25)
        - Taliesen West, 1947 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 26)
        - "Woods at Fisherman's Wharf," 1940 (Box 18 (hol), Folder 27)
        - Unidentified, undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 28)
      - Places (Box 18 (hol), Folder 29)
        - New York, undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 30)
        - Unidentified, undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 31)
      - Textiles (Box 18 (hol), Folder 32)
        - By Liebes, undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 33)
        - Liebes Exhibition Installations, undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 34)
        - Interiors Featuring Liebes Textiles, undated (Box 18 (hol), Folder 35)